<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Lucas Nethercott &#8211; Seeking Truth</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/lsneth/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 18:41:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/logo.png</url>
	<title>Lucas Nethercott &#8211; Seeking Truth</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Peace Among the Pieces</title>
		<link>/2024/12/06/peace-among-the-pieces/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Nethercott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 18:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, I want to share a metaphor that has helped me better understand the journey of learning and living the gospel. Imagine the gospel as a magnificent jigsaw puzzle with millions of pieces. The Savior has given us the completed picture on the puzzle’s box—a glimpse of &#8220;all truth, circumscribed into one great whole.&#8221; Our [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="4096" height="4096" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/jesus.png" alt="" class="wp-image-20"/></figure>



<p>Today, I want to share a metaphor that has helped me better understand the journey of learning and living the gospel.</p>



<p>Imagine the gospel as a magnificent jigsaw puzzle with millions of pieces. The Savior has given us the completed picture on the puzzle’s box—a glimpse of &#8220;all truth, circumscribed into one great whole.&#8221; Our leaders, the latter-day prophets and apostles, hold up this picture to guide us.</p>



<p>Each puzzle piece represents an idea, a doctrine, a question, or even a doubt about the gospel. Some pieces are foundational, forming the borders of the puzzle: the restoration of the gospel, the plan of salvation, or the Atonement of Jesus Christ. As we fit these foundational pieces together, they create the framework within which all other truths find their place.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Stray Puzzle Piece</h2>



<p>As we work on this spiritual puzzle, we occasionally encounter a piece that doesn’t seem to fit anywhere. We search for its place but can’t see where it belongs. From our limited perspective, it may seem as though this piece came from a different puzzle entirely. At such moments, we face a choice.</p>



<p>The first option is to fixate on the one piece that doesn’t seem to fit. If we focus all our attention on this single piece, our frustration will grow, and doubt will creep in. We might start questioning not only the piece itself but the entire picture on the box. Our uncertainty can overshadow the beauty of what we already accomplished. This fixation can leave us stuck, unable to move forward, and blind to the things we already know to be correct.</p>



<p>The second option is to set the challenging piece aside—for now—and focus on the many pieces we’ve already placed successfully. As we continue building, we find joy in the clarity and harmony emerging from the puzzle. Each new piece strengthens our understanding and confidence in the design of the picture.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Revisiting the Unmatched Pieces</h2>



<p>The pieces we set aside are not meant to be forgotten, however. At some point, they will contribute to our spiritual growth and understanding; they will become a part of our picture. As we revisit these challenging pieces with patience and faith, we often find that the progress we’ve made in other areas provides the perspective we need. What once seemed like a tree branch might reveal itself to be a deer antler.</p>



<p>The act of revisiting these pieces reminds us that questions and uncertainties are not threats to our faith but opportunities for it to deepen. Each time we approach these pieces again, we do so with greater trust in the divine Artist of this masterpiece. We come to realize that every piece, even the ones that once seemed confusing, has a place in the grand design of absolute truth.</p>



<p>As we practice this, our unmatched pieces can transform from wavering doubts into faithful questions. We can come to find peace among the pieces.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Trusting the Divine Artist</h2>



<p>God is not a distant puzzle maker, but the divine Artist who lovingly works with us as we piece together this work of eternal beauty. He inspires our minds and guides our hands as we come to comprehend something far more magnificent than we can imagine.</p>



<p>The Savior’s promise is sure: “Peace I leave with you, my peace I give unto you: not as the world giveth, give I unto you. Let not your heart be troubled, neither let it be afraid” (<a href="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/nt/john/14?id=p27#p27">John 14:27</a>). This peace, and the lack of fear that accompanies it, does not come from understanding every piece immediately, but from trusting in the One who knows how every piece fits together.</p>



<p>Let us trust in Heavenly Father. Let us look to the completed picture His servants hold up. And let us focus on the pieces of Christ&#8217;s gospel that we already know to be true. As we do so, I testify that we will come to find peace among the pieces. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
